

PROFILE

Over 8 years of experience leading teams on and offshore, customer relations, UX Design, mobile and web development for consumer and internal applications. Solid understanding of mobile and web related technologies along with object-oriented design and frameworks. Experience providing technical expertise, problem solving, collaborating with clients and development teams, NLP, machine learning and big data.

EXPERIENCE

O9/2013 - Present Sparkway Corporation (http://sparkway.com), Solution Architect
Sparkway Inc. is a technology company that helps clients develop strategic initiatives & custom software solutions. We specialize in Big Data and NLP. I developed several applications using Node, Angular, HTML5, Objective-C, Java, PHP, Mongo, MySQL, Bluemix and AWS cloud services.

Last worked project included developing a client-facing app for beauty scheduling within metropolitan areas, called Beauty Booked (https://www.beautybooked.com/home). The application was build using Angular and Node for desktop admin users, RoR for the client app and Swift for mobile app.

11/2012 - 9/2013 InfoStretch (http://infostretch.com), Software Engineer

InfoStretch provides services in design, development and QA testing for mobile apps. InfoStretch has been providing expert mobile solutions and services since 2004 to various enterprises to help them mobilize, monetize and thrive.

Last worked project included developing a Cordova and Node application for client ISOS (http://app.lk/sos-member). This application was build for iOS, Android, Windows and BlackBerry.

09/2008 - 11/2012 The District (http://philasd.org), Senior Web Developer

The District is the eighth largest school district in the nation, by enrollment. While there I was in charge of maintaining the district's website and district's 250 school websites. Also played a key role in technology advancements and application development.

Last worked project included developing a JS, HTML5, PHP, and Java app called School Profiles (https://webapps.philasd.org/school profile). The application let's concern stakeholders find information about certain schools within the District.

EDUCATION

2004-2006 | Montgomery County College, Blue Bell, PA Bachelor Accreditation (Non-Degree) Computer Science

2003-2004 | Elim Bible Institute, Lima, NY

Completed one-year program in International Culture & Missions

1999-2003 | Montgomery County College, Pottstown, PA Associate Degree in Computer Graphics and Fine Arts (A.A.S)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, CSS3, HTML5, PHP, MySQL, Objective-C, Swift, LUA, SVG, NodeJS, MongoDB

Libraries: React, AngularJS, Express, Mongoose, Cordova, Bootstrap, D3, SASS, Corona

Software: Sketch, Xcode, Illustrator, Photoshop, Flash, Indesign, Wordpress, Garageband and iMovie

Operating Systems/Servers: iOS, Android, Linux, Unix, Apache HTTP, Apache Tomcat

Artistic Mediums: Graphite Pencils and Charcoal

Other: NLP, Big Data, Machine Learning, Fluent in Mandarin, Beginner Japanese

DEVELOPMENT SAMPLES

Online Portfolio: http://cakers5559.github.io/portfolio GitHub Account: https://github.com/cakers5559